In this section we're going to discuss some methods you can use in dealing with tough customers.
A very important thing to remember when you are dealing with a tough customer and this is a very difficult thing to do, stay calm.
The customer comes at you with a very upset loud tone; don't match the customers tone.
The customer is yelling at you.
Maintain a regular tone of professionalism just general conversation much like I'm doing right now.
In my experience, people will bring their tone down to match the others persons tone rather than trying to escalate it.
If you stay calm, you can help that customer stay calm.
The worst thing that I can do is to become angry right along with them.
Then this doesn't become just an issue about what the customer wants you to solve or question that the customer has, then it becomes a very personal argument.
That crosses a completely different line so you have to stay calm, stay professional most times just by doing that and using the proper professional tone you can defuse a situation and you will calm a customer down.